(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-31T23:14:26.749118",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Base instincts take control
Like primal ways of a warrior
Is it glory you're after, like me?
Underestimated everywhere I turn
Taking aim, but it doesn't make a difference at all
I got a million different enemies I cannot recall
You're rocking up to a battle when you know that you'll fall
Hidden motivation, watch it all burn
And I gotta tell you
I never liked you
Now, would I lie to you?
Let me ignite you
When thunder crashes down
When the world caves under my pressure
There'll be no one to save
Where is your pride, your human will to survive?
Was it just empty words for your grave?
I reach inside this soul
Now all that remains
Is delusion and decay
'Cause of you, I live this way
We're not rivals!
We're not equals!
You're just confused!
lightning never strikes twice in the same spot
so go ahead and run up on me 'til you get your shot
i see the weapon that you're hiding, come on, ready or not
another life and you would never give a second thought
thinkin' your pride's different than mine
tickin' all your vital signs off
but we still gotta protect all our friends from our enemies
wouldn't you agree? Yeah!
forged in fires of hell, god can't betray you
if I'm a fallen angel, what does that make you?
I'm not debasing myself to see the same view
when it's your pride on the line, no one can save you from mine
We're not rivals!
We're not equals!
Hello 皆さん！ Yeah, yeah! Woo!
Hello everyone! Yeah, yeah! Woo!
This is... Woo! Thank you!
This is Mori Calliope! 森カリオペです！
This is Mori Calliope! I am Mori Calliope!
Thank you so much everybody for coming to my birthday live!
Here's the hashtag #UNCUTROCK, right here, right here, right here!
Check it out everybody!
Today's theme is obviously birthday, right? It's my birthday!
And so, if you look behind us, we've got stones!
Oh my gosh! What kind of stones I wonder? Maybe birthday stones, depending on the guest I suppose.
Well, Mori Calliope is diamond.
So, of course, you will see white.
Behind me, yes, and the idea is to sing original songs with guests,
and also my own songs, and I'm looking at the comments right now.
Now, the show is in very high quality, so there's like a pretty big lag, but I'm looking.
Woo! Woo! Phew, there's a lot of clapping.
Jeez, holy cannoli!
Holy cannoli is right. こんばんは！こんばんは！
Holy cannoli is right. Good evening! Good evening!
コメント見てます！
I'm reading the comments!
Wow, すごい！Happy birthday, happy birthday!
Wow, amazing! Happy birthday, happy birthday!
Happy birthday wish ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for the happy birthday wishes!
And you know what? Behind me is not only stones, but...
I also have a fabulous band joining me!
Yes, that's right! Live band!
Thank you so much to the band for coming. Now...
In particular, we have somebody that Calliope really respects.
Today Park-san is here with us!
カリちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Calli-chan, happy birthday!
Thank you!
今日もよろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to working with you today as well!
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to working with you as well!
Park-san is a one of my favorite bass players ever.
Park-san is one of my favorite bass players ever.
He's done two songs for me,
in particular, "Orpheus" and "Sepia". オルフェウスとセピアのベースやってくれました。
in particular, "Orpheus" and "Sepia". He played bass for "Orpheus" and "Sepia".
Park-sanはすごいリスペクトしてます。はい。
I really respect Park-san. Yes.
But I have so many wonderful members in the band today and also guests as well,
and I don't want to take up too much more time, but...
Anyway, we should probably sing with guests,
because I want to showcase all that we've been practicing together. So...
Let's go ahead and begin!
The first guest... Come on!
I can't control myself
[Song: I can't control myself]
閉ざした世界
In a closed-off world...
かすかに聞こえる音
...a faint sound can be heard...
世界で二人きりみたいだ
...it feels like it's just the two of us in this world.
届きそうな手
Hands that seem within reach...
すれ違った心が
...our drifting hearts...
ちょっと痛むんだ
...hurt just a little.
ここで待って
Wait for me here.
決められないままで
Still unable to decide...
戸惑い溢れてしまうよ
...confusion overflows.
もう何度も繰り返した
Repeated so many times now...
こぼれた想いを数えて
...counting the spilled feelings...
何度も繰り返した
...repeated so many times...
世界
World,
world,
開くのを待っている
waiting for it to open.
壊れた世界
In a broken world...
周り続ける針は
...the hands that keep spinning...
ちぎれた意識 繋いでいく
...connect our frayed consciousness.
歪んだ金属音
A distorted metallic sound...
鳴り響く心に
...resonating in my heart...
ちょっと響くんだ
...echoes just a little.
ここで待って
Wait for me here.
記憶繋げないまま
With memories unconnected...
狂って 壊れてしまうよ
I'm going crazy, I'm going to break down
もう何度も繰り返した
How many times have I repeated this?
神様に願いをかけて
Praying to God...
何度も繰り返した
Repeated so many times...
世界 世界
World, world...
開くのを待っている
Waiting for it to open...
もう何にも要らないから
Because I don't need anything anymore,
こぼれ落ちた思いは 幻
My spilled feelings are just an illusion.
何度も繰り返した
Repeated over and over,
世界 世界
world, world...
開くのを
waiting...
もう何度も繰り返した
How many times have I repeated this?
神様に願いをかけて
Praying to God...
何度も繰り返した
Repeated over and over,
世界 世界
world, world...
開くのを待っている
Waiting for it to open...
最初のゲストはAZKi先輩です！
Our first guest is AZKi-senpai!
右手にマイク 左手に地図 あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！
Mic in my right hand, map in my left hand, zero-guessing your heart!
カリオペちゃん ハッピーバースデー！
Calliope-chan, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！バースデーです！誕生日です！
Thank you so much! It's my birthday!
誕生日カリ...
Birthday Cal...
ありがとうございます！さっき一緒に歌った曲、大好きです！
Thank you! I love the song we just sang together!
ありがとうございます！なんとAZKiのオリジナル曲を一緒に歌わせていただきました！
Thank you! We got to sing AZKi's original song together!
そうですよ、ずっとバンドアレンジで歌いたかったから選んだの！
That's right! I chose it because I've always wanted to do a band arrangement!
めっちゃ熱かったです！
It was so awesome!
やったー！
Yay!
楽しかったよね！バンドの演奏もすごかったです！
It was so fun! The band's performance was amazing too!
ありがとうございます！イェーイ！
Thank you! Yay!
ちなみに、ステージを見てほしい！
By the way, I want you to look at the stage!
いや、すごい！めちゃくちゃピカピカ光ってる！
Wow, incredible! It's shining so brightly!
ピカピキストーン！ピカピキストーン！
Shiny stones! Shiny stones!
そうですよね、めっちゃ素敵ですよね！
Right? It's super wonderful!
素敵なステージです！
It's a wonderful stage!
ちなみに、AZKi先輩の誕生石は知ってる...？
By the way, do you know AZKi-senpai's birthstone...?
AZKiの誕生石は7月なんですけど... ルビー！ルビー！この色！
My birthstone is for July... Ruby! Ruby, this color!
そう、なりました！
That's right, it changed to this!
すごい！色が変わるんですね、今日は！
Awesome! The color changes today, right?
そうですよね、めっちゃ素敵ですよね！
Right? It's really wonderful!
すごい、めっちゃ赤です！
Awesome, it's super red!
そうですね、きれい！
Yeah, beautiful!
めっちゃきれいだから、一緒に写真撮りたい...
It's so pretty, I want to take a picture together...
あ、撮りたい！撮りたい！
Ah, I want to! I want to!
Take screenshots!
ピース！
Peace!
いい感じです！
Looking good!
イェーイ！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
じゃあ、生ライブだから、やっぱ水飲みたいと思う...
Well, since it's a live show, I think we should drink water...
水飲もう！
Let's drink water!
水乾杯！
Water toast!
はい、乾杯！
Alright, cheers!
乾杯！ Cheers!
Cheers! Cheers!
OK, OK!
じゃあ、次の曲...
Now then, the next song...
お、次の曲は何かな？
Oh, what's the next song?
一曲ありますよね、一緒に！
We have one more song together, right?
あります！
We do!
さっきAZKi先輩のオリ曲歌いましたね。そうです！
Earlier we sang AZKi-senpai's original song. That's right!
今回はカリオペのオリ曲です！
This time, it's Calliope's original song!
歌わせていただきます！
We're going to sing it!
The next song is Calliope's original, 未来島 -Future Island-!
The next song is Calliope's original, Future Island!
危険な海に浮かぶ島 エッグヘッド
Egghead, an island floating in dangerous seas
世界変える未来島のラボフェーズ
The lab phase of the Future Island that will change the world
最高の頭脳
The greatest brain
叶えるよ願望
Fulfilling your desires
未来のお宝探していこう
Let's search for the treasures of the future
天才が引き起こす発想の奇跡
The miracle of ideas sparked by a genius
脳内で終わらせない夢のファンタジー
A dream fantasy that won't just end in the mind
世界がひっくり返るテクノロジー
Technology that turns the world upside down
大体叶えちゃうラボラトリー
A laboratory that makes almost anything come true
釈迦 リリス エジソン ピタゴラス アトラス ヨーク 6人のサテライト
Shaka, Lilith, Edison, Pythagoras, Atlas, York: the six Satellites
湧き出すアイデア 止まらない
Ideas gushing out, never stopping
忙しすぎて 猫の手も借りたい
So busy, we could use any extra pair of hands
海も波も超えてゆく海賊王
The Pirate King who braves the seas and waves
常識変えてゆく発明王
The King of Invention changing common sense
そんな奴らに憧れてきた
I've always admired those kind of people
次は誰が王になる？
Who will be the next king?
無限の夢
Boundless dreams
未来の知恵
Wisdom of the future
ひらめきを巻き起こせ
Spark a revolution of inspiration
エッグヘッド
Egghead!
無限の夢
Boundless dreams
未来の知恵
Wisdom of the future
過去も世界も飛び越して
Soaring beyond both past and world
ベガパンク
Vegapunk!
生み出すよアイデア
I'll create ideas
ベガパンク
Vegapunk!
Vegapunk
革命をここから
Revolution starts right here
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
危険な海に浮かぶ島
An island floating in dangerous seas...
エッグヘッド
Egghead!
世界変える未来島のラボ
The lab on Future Island changing the world!
This mind is undefeated
And until my goals completed
Let's keep on searching for the treasure of to come
Genius, a miracle, a leader gotta set it free
Standard, fantastic dreams are burning up inside of me
Brilliant, will turn the world around with new technology
Kilter, elaborate story cast upon the sea
Proof turns into evil and the contents of mind
Ridin' to knowledge greeted by a lonely satellite
Ideas can't stop gushing, I'll stop thinkin' they might
Could use a hand at tool, I'm busy workin' into the night
The pirate king who braves the ocean while in search of elation
A ruler of invention that can modify all reason
Once washed in jealousy, someday I've got to be
Next on the throne, I know what I've got to do
無限の夢ね
Because of dreams,
未来の知恵
wisdom of the future!
ひらめきを咲き誇らせて
Let inspiration bloom in full glory!
無限の夢ね
Because of dreams,
未来の知恵
wisdom of the future!
過去の世界も飛び越して
Leaping past even the past world!
ベガパンク 生み出すよアイデア
Vegapunk, generating new ideas!
ベガパンク
Vegapunk!
ベガパンク 革命をここから
Vegapunk, revolution starts right here!
ベガパンク
Vegapunk!
Thank you so much! Bye bye! See you later!
Thank you so much! Bye-bye! See you later!
Dancing Reed
[Song: Dancing Reed]
All right!
Everybody welcome to the stage, Sora-senpai!
Happy birthday!
Yeah!
Okey dokey 返事はいいけど
Okey dokey, the answer is fine,
冗談なら笑えないよ
but if it's a joke, I can't laugh.
渋滞 曖昧 どっちを向いちゃうの
Traffic, ambiguity, which way are you looking?
蜃気楼に手を伸ばした
I reached out to the mirage.
微熱のような
A dream story...
夢物語
...like a slight fever.
そんな光は見ない振りしていた
I was pretending not to see such light.
ざわめく鼓動 まだ行かないで
The thumping heartbeat, don't go yet.
幻じゃ嫌だよ 私を奪って
I hate it if it's an illusion. Take me away.
魅惑の dancing dancing night
Enchanting dancing dancing night.
拡がって 収まんない universe
Expanding, unstoppable universe.
君の表情は私の森羅万象を
Your expression might rewrite all my microcosm,
書き換えちゃうかも 責任重大ね
the responsibility is huge.
一切合切 dance dance dance we are dancing reed
Everything, dance dance dance, we are dancing reed.
夢中になって絡み合った ゼログラビティ
Getting lost and intertwined zero gravity.
構わず dance dance dance just a dance just a dance
Regardless, dance dance dance, just a dance, just a dance.
声は闇に預けたまま
I left my voice in the darkness.
目を覚ましても 離れないで
Even if I wake up, don't leave me.
Maybe needy 正気じゃないのよ
Maybe needy, I'm not sane.
体温が忘れられない
I can't forget your body temperature.
誰彼そんなんじゃないから
It's not just anyone,
独り占めして euphoria
so I'll hog you, euphoria.
気に流してない様な言葉は装飾で
Words that seem like I don't care are just decorations.
メイクの様には流せない
Like makeup, I can't wash it off.
360° 偽りだって
360 degrees, even if it's a lie,
隠し切れぬような 私にかまって
I can't hide it. Pay attention to me.
嬉しいなんて crazy crazy love
Saying I'm happy is crazy crazy love.
摩天楼から連れさらって
Take me away from the skyscraper.
君の表情は私の深層心理を
Your expression might swap my deep psychology,
すり替えちゃうのよ 責任重大ね
the responsibility is huge.
過ぎ去ったネオン 残像 shooting star
Neon that has passed, afterimage, shooting star.
グライダーみたいに漂えば 幸も不幸もなかった
If I float like a glider, there was no happiness or unhappiness.
指先でまた君を探している
I'm looking for you again with my fingertips.
その声を聴かせてよ
Let me hear that voice.
私にかまって
Pay attention to me,
教えてよ 恋の先を
tell me what lies beyond love.
広がり収まらない universe
An ever-expanding universe,
君の存在は 私の将来までも
your presence reaches into my future,
踏み込んだのよ 付き合ってよね
stepping right in—so stay with me.
一切合切
Everything, completely.
Dance dance dance, we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合った ゼログラビティ
Obsessed and intertwined in zero gravity,
構わず
regardless...
Dance dance dance, just a dance, just a dance
声は闇に預けたまま
Leaving our voices to the darkness,
目を覚ましても離れないで
even if I wake up, don't leave my side.
Yes! Our second guest is Sora-senpai!
はい！みんな感謝して聞きなされ！カリちゃん、Happy Birthday!
Hi! Everyone, listen with gratitude! Calli-chan, Happy Birthday!
Thank you!
そら大先輩！来てくれてありがとうございます！ずっと一緒に歌いたかったから...
Sora-daisenpai! Thank you so much for coming! I've wanted to sing with you for so long...
あ、本当ですか？ありがとう！
Ah, really? Thank you!
嬉しっすよ、マジで！やった！
I'm so happy, seriously! Yay!
Hey hey hey!
可愛いよね！
Isn't she cute!
すごい！そして、すごい沢山踊りました！
Amazing! And we danced so much!
あ、踊ったね！
Ah, we sure did!
ね！アイドル、わお！ドキドキ！
Right! An idol, wow! So nervous!
ドキドキ？
Nervous?
あ、カリ、X... X...
Ah, Calli, X... X...
X trending number 3 in Japan!
Thank you so much! It's trending number 3 in Japan!
え、Congratulations!
Eh, congratulations!
トレンド、やった！
Trending, yay!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
たくさんつぶやいてね、Please, hashtag!
Tweet a lot, please! Use the hashtag!
Thank you so much! Ah, I'm so happy!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Yay! そして、なんか今回...
Yay! And this time...
大好きな曲、一緒に歌いました！
We sang one of my favorite songs together!
Dancing Reed!
Wow, すごいなんかパーティー、ハッピー！嬉しいよね、大好きです！
Wow, it felt like such a happy party! I'm so glad, I love it!
ダンサブル！
So danceable!
めっちゃよかった！
It was so good!
ほら、エメラルド来た！
Look, emerald came up!
ねー！綺麗、緑！
Right! Beautiful green!
誕生石ですよね！
It's the birthstone!
そう！5月の誕生石、エメラルドです！
Yes! May's birthstone is emerald!
Emerald! Wow, すごい良い発音！
Emerald! Wow, your pronunciation is great!
Nice English, very good!
そうですよね。ちなみに、写真撮ろっか？
Right. By the way, shall we take a picture?
あ、撮る！ Let's do it!
Oh, let's take one! Let's do it!
いいですね！
Looks good!
Yay!
写真もアップしてね、X！
Post the photos on X too!
よろしくねー！
Please do!
楽しい！じゃあ、水飲みましょう！
So fun! Now, let's drink some water!
あ、水！いいんですか？乾杯！
Ah, water! Can we? Cheers!
飲んだ方がいいっすよねー
It's definitely better to drink water.
そうね、水は大事！そうだよ！はぁー、楽しい生ライブ！
Yeah, water is important! That's right! Ah, live streams are so fun!
もう一曲一緒に歌いたいんですけど、大丈夫ですか？
I'd love to sing one more song together, is that okay?
Let's do it, okay. Now, everyone, please listen to this next song.
You'll understand why I chose it, because Sora-senpai is in the PV for this song.
Please enjoy my オリ曲, Dawn Blue.
Please enjoy my original song, "Dawn Blue."
つかまえて ほら この shooting star
Catch it, look, this shooting star.
A world of our fiction awaits...
ずっと同じ毎日に迷いがあっても
Even if I strayed in the same everyday routine,
気づかないふりをしてたんだ
I pretended not to notice.
ほんの少しの勇気がまだ出せなくって
Unable to find even a little bit of courage,
まどろむ宇宙で彷徨っていた
I drifted through a slumbering universe.
夜空に浮かぶ 星に願いをかけるんだ
I'll make a wish on the stars floating in the night sky.
I hope...
抱いてる夢を 絶対諦めたくない
I never want to give up on the dream I hold.
走り出すから
Because I'm starting to run,
追いかけて 今 あの shooting star
chasing after that shooting star right now.
見たことのないストーリー 進んでいくんだ
Moving forward into an unseen story,
いつの日にかきっと 描いた世界へ 辿り着けるように
so that one day we can surely reach the world we envisioned.
Go, let go of the days you thought mattered so, life goes on, tomorrow's rolling in
A dream we sought so long
僕ら 誰でもない 自分になりたいんだ
We want to become someone who is uniquely ourselves.
新しい風が 心を揺らした
A new wind stirred our hearts.
It takes something to believe
the wish we were promised could really come to life.
And so, if this is how the story goes,
you'll find that strength inside, I'll remember who I was back then.
Reach for my hand and hear it!
構えて ほら この瞬間を重ね
Get ready, see, let's stack these moments together.
さあ まずは一歩踏み出して
Now, first take a step forward,
恐れずに行こう
and let me go without fear.
いつの日にかきっと
Someday, for sure...
まだ見ぬ世界へ
...to an unseen world...
辿り着けるように
...so that we can reach it.
夜明けに咲いた月が
The moon that bloomed at dawn...
眩しいブルーの空に溶けていく
...melts into the dazzling blue sky.
You and I and the undecided future,
doesn't matter if the final truth hurts.
もうすぐ朝が動き出すから
Because morning will start moving very soon.
抱きしめて 今
Embrace it now,
この瞬間を
this moment...
見たことのないストーリー
...a story never seen before.
I'll be here betting on that fear, so hard,
'cause you're that shooting star.
It's hopeless, now or maybe if you take that step,
into the darkness you'll find me.
Running by your side until the dawn!
In the end it's you and me,
us against tomorrow.
It's the world that we had dreamed.
Dry your eyes and don't look back!
Thank you so much Sora-senpai! また一緒に歌いましょう！
Thank you so much, Sora-senpai! Let's sing together again!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Thank you! Bye-bye! またねー！
Thank you! Bye-bye! See you!
またねー！
See you!
See you! わー、楽しいね、生ライブ！
See you! Wow, live performances are so fun!
Oh man, this is so fun. I just love singing. I love singing. I have so much... and you guys, thank you for being a part of it. Woo, nailed it! You think so?
Because Sora-senpai was by my side. It was awesome.
Now next, I'll be singing with a surprise secret guest, but it's a bit of a break for myself and the band right now because we're gonna go back in time to a time when I recorded something with a special guest with the power of technology.
You'll understand what I mean, but let's go back in the past, and myself and the band are gonna chill for a minute.
You'll understand what I mean, but let me go back in the past, and myself and the band are gonna chill for a minute.
So please enjoy that special guest performance, and I'll see you guys soon for the next live one very shortly.
Okay. See you then, どうぞ！
Okay, see you then! Here you go!
罪と蜜 (feat. Mori Calliope)
[Song: Sin and Honey (feat. Mori Calliope)]
絆創膏に落ちたんだ けどきっと不幸に落ちたんだ
I fell for an adhesive bandage, but surely I fell into misfortune.
気づきゃ僕らはこれを呼んでいた
Before we knew it, we were calling this...
あなたの錯覚によるものだったんだ 見事さ
It was all due to your optical illusion. Brilliant.
地獄のカタログ Recycled by Grim Reaper
Catalog of Hell, recycled by Grim Reaper.
今夜 本能 弄ろ
Tonight, indulge your instincts gracefully.
さながら脳に数枚のチップ 埋め込むような強愛のキック
Like embedding a few chips into the brain, a kick of intense love.
あたしあなたの永久のVIP 囁いた言葉はずっと離れずに
"I'm your permanent VIP," the whispered words never leave me.
あなたに あなたに あなたに 討ち果たし一人になれますか
To you, to you, to you, after defeating you, can I be alone?
Rot you, left me, ice, you're so sweet, we did it, did it, did it, stop!
Rot you, left me, ice, you're so sweet... did it did it stop!
I love, you're my girl! I love, you're my boy!
あなたを知る全ては過去になる
Everything that knows you becomes the past.
I love, you're my girl! I love, you're my boy!
幸せに満ちた未来 作ろうね
Let me create a future full of happiness.
愛しすぎてどうにくなりそうな僕を
Me, who is about to go crazy loving you too much...
愛しすぎてどうにくなりそうな私を
...me, who is about to go crazy loving you too much...
Give me give me give me give me love
Yeah, yeah, alright, listen up, let's go, come on
決してあたしに退屈させないで
Don't ever let me get bored.
とびきりのドレスとあなたのエスコート
An extraordinary dress and your escort.
敷き詰められた絨毯の上歩く
Walking on the carpet spread beneath.
望んじゃいないけどあたしはスター
I didn't ask for it, but I'm a star.
わがままな女のアクセサリー
An accessory for a selfish woman.
嫌がる男のデリカシー
The delicateness of a reluctant man.
世界で一番のお姫様
The world's number one princess.
3, 2, 1
ママに内緒 インダス 薔薇のタトゥー 口移し流し込む罪の味
A rose tattoo hidden from mom, pouring in the taste of sin with a kiss.
共犯ね これでアナタは
We're accomplices now; with this, you...
アタシに アタシに アタシに ふさわしいヒトになりました
...have become someone worthy of me, of me, of me.
Right you, left me, 愛す you So we did it, did it, did it, did it, stop
Right you, left me, loving you, so we did it, did it, did it, did it, stop.
I love you my girl I love you my boy 裏表 アナタ 僕 罪と蜜
I love you my girl, I love you my boy. Two sides of a coin, you and me, sin and honey.
I love you my girl I love you my boy その味知る前には戻れない
I love you my girl, I love you my boy. We can't go back to before tasting it.
そう 愛してみてもっと こんな僕を 愛してみてもっと こんなアタシを Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme love
So love me more, someone like me. Love me more, someone like me. Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme love.
Hey! Hey! Come on everybody! All right!
皆さん Welcome, syudouさんとCalliope 3D Birthday Live!
Welcome everyone to syudou-san and Calliope's 3D Birthday Live!
Thank you! Hey!
壊し合うように 癒し合うように 求め合ってしまうのよ しょうがないじゃない
As if destroying each other, as if healing each other, we seek each other—it can't be helped.
与えられた天国より 選んだ地獄を アナタと2人 奈落まで
Rather than a given heaven, I'd choose hell with you, all the way into the abyss.
I love you my girl I love you my boy ただ堕ちていく
I love you my girl, I love you my boy. We're simply falling.
I love you my girl I love you my boy アナタを知って全ては過去になる
I love you my girl, I love you my boy. Knowing you makes everything else the past.
I love you my girl I love you my boy しあーせに満ちた未来を作ろうね
I love you my girl, I love you my boy. Let's create a future full of happiness.
そう 愛し切ってどうか こんな僕を
So love me completely, someone like me.
愛し切ってどうか こんなアタシを Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme love
Love me completely, someone like me. Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme love.
そう 愛し合ってしまったこんな僕ら
So, having fallen in love like this...
ハッピーエンドに別れを告げ Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme love
...we bid farewell to happy endings. Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme love.
皆さん、どう思いましたかー？
Everyone, how was that?
ありがとうございます！ 楽しかったー！
Thank you so much! That was so much fun!
スーパースペシャルゲスト、syudouさんが来ましたー！
Our super special guest, syudou-san, is here!
こんにちはー！ Dead Beatsの皆さんこんにちは、syudouです！
Hello! Hello to all the Dead Beats, I'm syudou!
イエス！自己紹介お願いします！
Yes! Please introduce yourself!
はい、ミュージシャンやってますsyudouでございます。指して、ハッピーバースデーCalliopeさん！
Yes, I'm syudou, a musician. And Happy Birthday, Calliope-san!
おめでとう！ センキュー！ありがとうございます！ ライブも最高です！
Congratulations! - Thank you! Thank you so much! - The live show is amazing too!
あ、ちなみにハイタッチしたい！いいんですか？
Ah, by the way, I want to high-five! Is that okay?
あ、いきますか？いきますか？ はい、せーの！ よいしょ！
Oh, shall we? Shall we? - Alright, ready, set... - There we go!
イエーイ！ いい感じー！ありがとうございます！
Yeah! That was great! Thank you so much!
ちなみにsyudouさんは音楽活動いろいろやってます。どんな活動やってますか？
By the way, syudou-san does various musical activities. What kind of work do you do?
僕はボカロPですね。ボカロで楽曲を作ったり、シンガーソングライターとして歌ったり、楽曲提供をしたりしています。
I'm a Vocaloid producer. I write songs with Vocaloid, sing as a singer-songwriter, and write songs for others.
もちろん私知ってるけど、大ファンだからね！
Of course I knew that, since I'm a huge fan!
嬉しい！ライブも以前来ていただきまして。
I'm so glad! You even came to my live concert before.
そうですね！武道館ライブめっちゃ楽しかった！
That's right! Your Budokan concert was super fun!
本当に僕も楽しくて、めちゃくちゃ盛り上がったんで嬉しいです、今日出られて。
I really had fun too, and the energy was amazing. I'm so happy to be here today.
こちらこそ、私もしゅごい…すごい嬉しいですね。このステージ、どう思いますか？
Likewise, I'm so... super happy to have you! What do you think of this stage?
これすごいですよね！高さも含めて…僕、高いとこ苦手なんで落ちないように気つけないとと思うんですけど、最高です！
It's incredible! Including the height... I'm a bit afraid of heights, so I need to be careful not to fall, but it's awesome!
かなり高いけど気をつけてね！ 下が見えないからマジでヤバい（笑）
It is pretty high, so be careful! - I can't see the ground, so it's crazy! (laughs)
そういえばテーマが誕生日だから、知りたいね。syudouさんの誕生日はいつですか？
Speaking of which, since the theme is birthdays, I'd like to know. When is your birthday, syudou-san?
僕の誕生日9月ですね。September。
My birthday is in September. September.
Septemberですね！Septemberの誕生日ストーンはサファイアです！
September! The birthstone for September is sapphire!
サファイア！ ほら、ステージはサファイア！…サファイア！ そういうことだったんだ！
Sapphire! - Look, the stage is sapphire! ...Sapphire! - Ah, so that's what it was!
僕に合わせていただいた？ありがとうございます！たまたまですけど、服も帽子も青で合ってたんで。
Did you match it for me? Thank you! It's a coincidence, but my clothes and hat happened to be blue too.
相性がいい！ 嬉しいですね！ めっちゃいい感じですね！
We're so compatible! - I'm so happy! - It feels so great!
次の曲は、syudouさんが書き下ろしてくれたやつですね。
The next song is the one syudou-san wrote for me.
Calliopeさんの楽曲が大好きなのはもちろん、カッコよくて強くて美しいところを引き出せるような楽曲として作らせていただきました。
Of course I love your music, and I wrote this song to bring out your cool, strong, and beautiful qualities.
めっちゃいい曲！本当に大好きな曲だから、マジで感謝してます！
It's such a great song! I really love it, so I'm seriously grateful!
今回、一緒に歌いたいと思います！ 初めてですね、一緒に歌うのは！
I'd like us to sing it together this time! - It's our first time singing together!
大丈夫ですか？ はい！じゃあ次の曲に行く前に、みんなに伝えたいことありますか？
Are you ready? - Yes! - Before we move to the next song, is there anything you'd like to tell everyone?
何度かコラボさせていただいてるんですけど、皆さんに温かく迎えていただいてすごく嬉しいです！皆さんも一緒に盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです！
We've collaborated a few times, and I'm so happy everyone welcomes me so warmly! I hope everyone gets hyped up with us!
コラボに呼んでいただいてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for inviting me to collaborate!
いえいえ！こちらこそ！
No, no! Likewise!
じゃあ、それで聴いてくださいね！でも、syudouさん！
Well then, please give it a listen! But syudou-san!
はい！
Yes!
紹介してください！
Please introduce it!
それではお聞きください
Then, please listen to...
Let's Just Crash!
Hey, hey, 皆さん！
Hey, hey, everyone!
Let's go!
Hey! Hey! Let's go!
You got 100 ears, but you don't look or listen!
In other words, you're useless, every last one of ya!
And that's why I'm gonna send your world to hell!
All of humanity!
最安・最擦っと登場
Making a cheap, quick entry,
そう云うのんじゃねえ
but that's not what this is about.
I'm just a heads up you'll forget, so don't waste your time...
...getting triggered because of a fucking train going off track!
Somebody's gotta pay while I live the dream like me now, I'm one you can't tame, huh?
低俗・低査定の天才
A lowbrow, low-rated genius—
そう云うのでいい
that's totally fine by me.
思いが募る場所に花は咲く
Flowers bloom where feelings run deep,
から...
so...
Let's ride! Get back, you trash!
限界の壁を
We're breaking through
ぶち破っていくんだ
the wall of limits! / Let's just crash!
頂から高みへ
From the summit to even higher heights,
Alright!
Lose control!
欲しがりそうな
Reaching out a hand
手を差し伸べて行く野郎は
like a greedy bastard... / Heads will roll!
誰だ一体 誰だ一体 誰だったとしても
Who the hell, who the hell, no matter who it is!
この理想は無理だろって
Even if someone says
誰が言ったとしても
this ideal is impossible,
叶えていこうぜ
let's make it come true!
Goodbye!
Yeah, yeah, 1, 2...
Listen!
正解・不正解の回答
Answers of right or wrong,
戸惑っていい
it's fine to be confused.
そんなのとうに超えた場所に俺は立っている
I'm standing in a place far beyond all that!
Meaningless problems, everybody's got 'em and they can't be satisfied until somebody's at the bottom, so what?
You think you're special 'cause you got some creative hunger? We ain't gettin' any younger, thinking "Let's just crash!"
心が通う
When hearts connect,
時には魂が
sometimes the soul...
叫ぶ
...screams out!
Get back, you trash!
限界の壁を
We're breaking through
ぶち破っていくんだ
the wall of limits! / Let's just crash!
頂から高みへ
From the summit to even higher heights,
俺が通る
I'm coming through,
今すぐに
right now!
Don't care!
Let's ride! Get back, you trash!
限界の壁を
We're breaking through
ぶち破っていくんだ
the wall of limits! / Let's just crash!
頂から高みへ
From the summit to even higher heights,
Alright!
Lose control!
欲しがりそうな
Reaching out a hand
手を差し伸べて行く野郎は
like a greedy bastard... / Heads will roll!
誰だ一体 誰だ一体 誰だったとしても
Who the hell, who the hell, no matter who it is!
この理想は無理だろって
Even if someone says
誰が言ったとしても
this ideal is impossible,
叶えていこうぜ
let's make it come true!
3, 2, 1, let's go!
syudouさん、ありがとうございました！
syudou-san, thank you so much!
Thank you, 骸骨 & Calliope!
Thank you, skeletons & Calliope!
叶えていこうぜ
Let me make it come true!
でも、まだまだ終わってないっすね、皆さん！
But we're not done yet, everyone!
All right!
Let's just crash!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
バイバイ、syudouさん！
Bye-bye, syudou-san!
バイバイ！ Thank you, DEAD BEATS & Calliope!
Bye-bye! Thank you, DEAD BEATS & Calliope!
Yeah, yeah! Peace!
Ah, everyone, that was so fun!
I really respect syudou-san as an artist.
He does a lot of his work himself for his songs—writes, composes, sings, everything.
He's really cool, so big ups to syudou-san!
But I think it is about time that maybe we get back...
...to the future, the present, where I'm performing with all my friends right now.
Yes, but that was a lot of fun.
As I thought! Right on time!
It looks like it's time for me to get back to the future...
...and go sing with all my friends again back in the present/future. I don't know, none of it makes any sense.
Let's go! See you there!
Walking an empty road
Nowhere for me to go
Lost and lonely
Yeah, it's only me
Burnt out like candlelight
Left blazing through the night
Melting slowly
Until nothing else is left of me
Colored in shades of grey
Watching the days pass in front of me
Longing to find a way
I can fly away
I'm drifting through this blue, blue world
It's always been clear to me
How cruel the world can be
My shadow's the only one beside me
No love to call my own
No notice on my phone
Sunken silence
Has engulfed the very life I lead
Colored in shades of grey
Watching the years pass in front of me
Memories I wish would stay
Always fade away
I'm lonely in this blue, blue world
Though my heart is torn
And my weary wings are worn
Just tonight
Can't I dream of a better life
With happiness in sight?
Colored in shades of grey
Watching my life pass in front of me
Maybe it's not too late
If I can't escape
I'll have to make my own way
Colored in shades of grey
Palette in hand, I can make a change
I'll try to find the strength
Take a breath and paint
Bring color to this blue, blue world
Wow, beautiful, Nerissa! You're so great!
Ah, thank you for coming!
After that emotional song, now we're all energetic.
Oh my god, hi everybody!
Hey, introduce yourself to the people real quick.
Thank you, thank you. It is my birthday!
But who is this lovely lady I'm singing with right now?
Who could I be?
Hi, darlings! This is hololive English -Advent-
Devilish Diva, the one, the only, Nerissa Ravencroft here with you today...
...at your birthday party!
Wow, かっこいい！ So cool!
Wow, so cool! So cool!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Wow, you're so awesome, Nerissa.
Thank you so much for letting me sing your Shoji Meguro song together with you!
We both have a Shoji Meguro original song!
It's my first time performing, I got to be with you!
It was so fun. It's always fun singing with a friend, so thank you for letting me be a part of it.
We got to harmonize, too!
I did my best to learn the harmonies and try and remember and stay consistent.
You impressed me! Thank you so much!
Well, I guess we ought to talk about your birthstone, 'cause now we're gonna talk about your birthday...
Do you know your birthstone is topaz?
Yes! It's so pretty! My birthday's November 21st, I'm a Scorpio...
And it's so pretty! And that matches your little hair clip!
So true! Oh my gosh, it just positively lights you up, you're glowing.
How about we take some pictures in front of the stone?
Yeah, let's do it! All right, here we go.
Peace? Peace? どちらでも！ Either one's good.
Peace? Peace? Either one's good!
Facing each other... Feel a little sexy. Oh, boa!
いい感じ！ Very nice!
Looking good! Very nice!
Use the hashtag! Please post lots of pictures, okay?
Actually, just so you know, Nerissa, Genta on the drums played for our original song, Overkill!
Oh my gosh! Thank you! ありがとう！ Genta, thank you!
Oh my gosh! Thank you! Thank you! Genta, thank you!
So awesome, really appreciate you, thank you. I feel very lucky and privileged to have you here.
Do you wanna drink of water before we start? That's a great idea.
Immediately, yes. お水... and...
Immediately, yes. Water... and...
Okay, yeah, I think we're ready for another song then, how about that?
Together, we can do anything! Yes, next up is Calliope's original song...
Please enjoy Orpheus!
All right! Thank you so much, Nerissa, for coming to hang out! Let's finish this off with a bang!
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though, my heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah! Thinking hurry up, Orpheus, time's a-wasting!
Show me what you really wanna do!
Another late night, aimless dreaming, the day to day starts to call
Still got like a million deadlines, still bleeding red wine, my back up against the wall
I got my headphones on, walk home is long, dragging feet like I'm born to lose
'Til somehow they're tapping along to you-know-who's song, a melody I can't refuse
I'm outta line, but it's fine, you don't know my name. Safe inside my own mind, I don't feel the shame, okay?
I know I get a little carried away, but we got music when there aren't any words to say!
'Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way, gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
Now I'm in distress, you got me possessed, I might be obsessed, so let me get a little something off my chest, look
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though, my heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah! Thinking hurry up, Orpheus, time's a-wasting!
Show me what you really wanna do!
Tonight, it's my turn to show you how obvious I can be
Sometimes it feels like you're playing that guitar for me and only me
Critics so loud, so predictable, they can't see what I can see, you're gonna wind up a star
You got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
'Cuz I'm not lying when I'm implying you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional, baby, this could be real love?
Give me one chance and I'll take, you make me dance the night away
Get us help
Now it's a game that I've played before, but with the way the scene changed, there is nothing you can blame me for
I'm talking TV screens, magazines, seen you in a couple dreams, pictures up on every padded wall and floor
You're always talking 'bout 'no time to desire a lover,' so why'd you paint your nails up in my favorite color?
I got an attitude just when it comes to you, so yeah, reality is kinda slipping out of tune
I'm never lost in the groove of somebody new, if it's devotion you're after, I'm staying true
So are you noticing me, noticing you, noticing me? No disillusion, but there's not a lot of guarantee
'Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way, gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
You're strumming next to me, and I'm in ecstasy, and for the rest of the week, I'm pressure free
Alright! I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though, my heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah! Thinking hurry up, Orpheus, time's a-wasting!
Show me what you really wanna do!
Tonight, it's my turn to show you how obvious I can be, so just as long as you keep playing that guitar...
Yeah!
Critics so loud, so predictable, they can't see what I can see, you're gonna wind up a star!
You got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
'Cuz I'm not lying when I'm implying you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional, baby, this could be real love!
Give me one chance and I'll take, you make me dance the night away
All right, everybody! Today we have a very special band that's gathered today!
They're so cool! Right? We gotta give 'em a proper introduction, Nerissa!
Yes we do! So let's do it! Are you guys ready to meet the band? Here we go! First up on the drums, we got...
Genta!
Then on the bass, it's Yu Park!
And on the guitarist, Yoshi!
And last but not least, tonight's manipulator is hana!
All right, Nerissa, let's take 'em out!
Sounds good! Here we go!
Our victory is gonna be golden
Taking space with the bass and drummin'
So let's blow this joint, and if the feeling's right
Then we can make a little music of our own tonight
Come on, our victory is gonna be golden
Taking space with the bass and drummin'
Why you walkin' away? I got a lot to say
Guess I'll save it for the next one!
I ain't tryin' to stress you, I must confess though
My heart's beatin' to our song
Oh yeah!
So hear me out, Orpheus, I'm thinkin' next time
I'll show you what I really wanna do
Bye, Nerissa!
Thanks for singin' with me!
Happy early birthday, Calli!
Yes! See you later, love you too, bye bye!
ねえ　あたしいつも勇気が足りないから
自分を大切にできないんだ
Hey, because I always lack courage,
I can't value myself.
痛い目を見ないと気づけやしないんだ
あーあ　今日もキャラメルペインです
If I don't go through pain, I can't even realize it.
Ah, it's caramel pain again today.
Caramel Pain
良い子でなんか居られないよ
だって世界はこんなにも極彩色で
I can't stay a good girl,
because the world is so colorful.
甘ったるくて苦いし　あ、待って頭痛いし
ヘトヘトで漂うだけの 24/7
It's sweet and bitter, ah wait, I have a headache,
24/7 of just drifting, exhausted.
ギリギリ感情抑えるなんてもう無理
このままではいられない日々
It's impossible to suppress my emotions anymore,
these days where I can't stay like this.
ちょっと怖いけど
It's a little scary, but...
置いてくよ　置いてくよ　置いてくよ
今まで手にしたイデオロギーもスタイルも
I'll leave it behind, leave it behind, leave it behind,
all the ideologies and styles I've held onto until now.
壊れちゃっても今がいいよ
だってあたしはあたしのままでずっといたいんだもん
Even if they break, now is fine,
because I want to stay as I am forever.
ルート？ムード？どうでもいーよ　トゥー ザ ネクスト
もっと危ないことしたら勝ちナンデショ
Route? Mood? I don't care, to the next.
If I do more dangerous things, I win, right?
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
フロム マイ ベッド　この胸の痛みだけ抱いて
Whatever I sacrifice, it can't be helped.
From my bed, hugging only the pain in my chest.
あーあ　今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, it's caramel pain again today.
ミルフィーユみたいにはぐらかしたって
いつかバレちゃうよ　腐っちゃうよ
Even if I brush it off like a mille-feuille,
someday it'll be exposed, it'll rot.
痛いとか素直に君に言えてれば
今頃何か変わってたのかもね
If only I could honestly tell you it hurts,
maybe something would have changed by now.
好きなアニメもなくなっちゃうし
The anime I love will disappear,
好きな人だって居なくなっちゃうんだ
and the person I love will disappear too.
寂しくなっちゃうな　あー
It gets lonely, ah...
大切なことはただ一つだけさ
There is only one important thing.
もう後悔しないように前を向いて
生きるということ
To live looking forward
so I don't regret it anymore.
置いてくよ　置いてくよ　置いてくよ
今まで手にしたイデオロギーもスタイルも
I'll leave it behind, leave it behind, leave it behind,
all the ideologies and styles I've held onto until now.
汚れちゃっても気にしないよ
だってあたしはあたしに恋していたいんだもん
I don't care if they get dirty,
because I want to be in love with myself.
愛してるよ　愛してるよ　愛してるよ
さよならなんて涙が出ちゃうけど
I love you, I love you, I love you.
Saying goodbye makes me cry, but...
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
フロム マイ ベッド　この胸の痛みだけ抱いて
Whatever I sacrifice, it can't be helped.
From my bed, hugging only the pain in my chest.
あーあ　今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, it's caramel pain again today.
ねえ　あたしいつも勇気が足りないから
自分を大切にできないんだ
Hey, because I always lack courage,
I can't value myself.
痛いくらいなら少し我慢するんだ
If it hurts, I'll just endure it a little.
あーあ　今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, it's caramel pain again today.
イェーイ！
Yeah!
すいせい、すいせい、すいせいが来たー！
Suisei, Suisei, Suisei is here!
やったー！
Yay!
久しぶりですけど、ウェルカム！おめでとう！
It's been a while, but welcome! Congratulations!
ありがとう！自己紹介お願いします！
Thank you! Please introduce yourself!
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの街プラ星街すいせいです！カリオペ、誕生日おめでとう！
It's the rough diamond of a star that appeared like a comet! Virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei! Happy birthday, Calliope!
ありがとうございます！誕生日でーす！
Thank you so much! It's my birthday!
そしてね、メジャーデビューも4周年？
And also, 4th anniversary of your major debut, right?
そうですよね！
That's right!
うわ、すごいよ、長い！おめでとう！
Wow, that's amazing, so long! Congratulations!
長いですよね！一緒に歌いましたよね！
It really is! We sang together back then too, right?
そう、4年前ね！メジャーデビューしたときのライブで！
Yeah, 4 years ago! At the concert for your major debut!
一緒に歌ってもらいましたね
I got to sing together with you!
懐かしい！
How nostalgic!
ねー、懐かしい！なん、こんなんもやってなかった？
Right? Nostalgic! Didn't we also do something like this?
やりました！たくさんやりました！
We did! We did it so much!
やばいよね、めっちゃいい思い出ですよねー
It's amazing, isn't it? Such great memories!
ねー！覚えててくれたね、それ
Yeah! You remembered that!
ねー、久しぶりに歌えて嬉しいね
Yeah, I'm glad we could sing together after so long!
懐かしいポイント！
A nostalgic moment!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そうですね、今回『Caramel Pain』一緒に歌いました。一番好きな星街すいせい曲です！
That's right, this time we sang "Caramel Pain" together. It's my absolute favorite Hoshimachi Suisei song!
わー嬉しい！イェーイ！やったー！
Wow, I'm so happy! Yay!
めっちゃいい感じだったね！ハモリとかもね！
It felt so good! The harmonies too!
たくさん練習しました！
We practiced a lot!
ねー！本当綺麗だったぜ！
Yeah! It was really beautiful!
ありがとうございます！ちなみにほら…
Thank you so much! By the way, look...
ピカピカストーン！
A sparkling stone!
Wow, beautiful!
うん、素敵ですよね！
Yeah, isn't it lovely?
素敵！
Lovely!
えー、すいせい先輩…あの、あたし知ってるけど、誕生日はいつですか？
Umm, Suisei-senpai... I mean, I know, but when is your birthday?
私は3月の22…
Mine is March 22nd...
March 22nd! 22nd!
そうですね。先月…
That's right. Last month...
そう、先月！
Yes, last month!
ですので、ほら、アクアマリンが…
So, look, aquamarine is...
あ！誕生石！アクアマリンだー！
Ah! The birthstone! It's aquamarine!
もうぴったりよね！私知らなかったよ！自分の誕生石がアクアマリンって！
It's so perfect! I didn't even know my birthstone was aquamarine!
そう、ぴったりですよ！マジで最高！
Yes, it's perfect! Honestly, it's the best!
ねー！同じ色だよ！
Right! It's the same color!
最高だぜ！
It's the best!
めっちゃ素敵ですよー！
It's super lovely!
ねー！めっちゃ綺麗だから、一緒に写真撮りましょう！
Right! It's so pretty, so let me take a picture together!
あ、撮ろう！いいですか？Let's go!
Ah, let's take one! Are you ready? Let's go!
Yeah!
あ、私ね、やりたいポーズある
Ah, there's a pose I want to do.
Okay.
あ、いいですね！
Oh, nice!
Okay, let's do it! Yeah!
これ分かる？何のポーズか
Do you know what pose this is?
No, Jojoじゃない？
No, is it JoJo?
違うよ
No, it's not.
What's this?
ゴールデンボール！
Golden Ball!
そう！
Exactly!
忘れてた！カッコいいよねー！
I forgot! It's cool, right?
ありがとう！Thank you so much!
Thank you! Thank you so much!
え、ちゃんと見てくれた？ありがとう！
Eh, did you watch it carefully? Thank you!
もちろん！大好きな曲ですし！
Of course! It's a song I love!
Thank you so much, 先輩！
Thank you so much, Senpai!
えー、ちなみに、Everybody, really quick, before we keep going, お知らせあります！
Umm, by the way, everybody, really quick, before we keep going, I have an announcement!
Yes, quick announcement about members-only. メンバーズ限定アンコールがありますよ！
Yes, quick announcement about members-only. We have a members-only encore!
やったー！
Yay!
A solo session! And we need to pick one song that I just performed with the amazing guests, and I'm going to do a solo version of it! Yes!
So you have 1 minute starting now! 1分ありますよ！Vote! あのカリオペはソロで歌いますよ！
So you have 1 minute starting now! You have 1 minute! Vote! Calliope will sing solo!
さっきゲストと一緒に歌った曲。Please vote! Everybody, you have 1 minute, go!
The songs I sang with the guests earlier. Please vote! Everybody, you have 1 minute, go!
いいですね！この後のメン限でソロで歌ってくれるらしいですよ！
That's great! Looks like she'll sing a solo version in the upcoming members-only stream!
Yes! えー、全部聴きたいよー！
Yes! Ah, I want to hear all of them!
そうだね！全部めっちゃめっちゃいい曲！すべての…
Right! They're all super good songs! All of them...
ねー！
Right!
でも、一曲だけ！
But only one song!
Only one! ね、一曲だけですよ。選んでくださいね！
Only one! Right, just one song. Please pick one!
なんでね、Please! お願いします！
So please, please!
誰が良いかな、誰が良いかな…
Which one is good, which one is good...
お願いします！楽しみ！頑張ります！
Please! I'm looking forward to it! I'll do my best!
ねー！いや、カリオペ本当にね…
Right! Ah, Calliope, really...
4…4年！メジャーデビューして4年！
4... 4 years! 4 years since your major debut!
本当に駆け抜けてきたよね！
You've really been running all out!
色々やってますよね！ねー！なんかアニメのタイアップとかもね！
I've been doing various things! Right, like anime tie-ins too!
たくさん決まって！来ました！
So many confirmed! It came!
ねー！嬉しい！It's my dream!
Right! So happy! It's my dream!
ねー！そうですね、夢が叶った！
Right! That's true, your dream came true!
すごい！めっちゃ嬉しい！ありがとうございます！皆さんのおかげで！
Amazing! I'm super happy! Thank you so much! Thanks to everyone!
素敵な先輩のおかげで！You're my inspiration! Thank you so much!
Thanks to wonderful senpai too! You're my inspiration! Thank you so much!
Everybody! Yay!
最高！So, let's keep shooting for the moon. Yeah.
Awesome! So, let's keep shooting for the moon. Yeah.
そうだよ！
That's right!
うん。
Yeah.
Oh, let's see. Oh, okay. Well, everybody is writing what they want... Oh, okay, すごいすごい！今…
Oh, let's see. Oh, okay. Well, everybody is writing what they want... Oh, okay, awesome, awesome! Right now...
好きな曲！おー、すごいすごい！
Their favorite songs! Oh, awesome, awesome!
ね！わー、すごい！Many, many, many, many!
Right! Wow, amazing! Many, many, many, many!
お、投票が…まだ？
Oh, the voting... is it still going?
Go, go, go! Choose, choose, choose! 選んで選んで！
Go, go, go! Choose, choose, choose! Pick one, pick one!
選んだ？嬉しい！
Did you choose? I'm happy!
始まってる？投票もう少し長くやりますってよ！
Has it started? They say voting will go on a little longer!
Okay, a little bit longer! Longer, longer time!
Yes, please choose one. It's hard, 難しいと思うけど…
Yes, please choose one. It's hard, I know it's hard, but...
Yeah, let's drink water! あ、確かに！
Yeah, let's drink water! Ah, indeed!
水乾杯！飲みましょう、はい！
Water cheers! Let's drink, yes!
Okay. Cheers!
Cheers! Thank you, Senpai.
ジャパニーズ…乾杯って何だと思う？
In Japanese... what do you think "cheers" is?
乾杯！
Kanpai!
乾杯！最近の流行りなんて言うと…
Kanpai! As for recent slang, what do people say...?
あー…乾杯…
Ah... Kanpai...
ケッピー！
KP!
KP! KPいいですね！え、たくさん使いたいと思う！
KP! KP is good! Ah, I want to use it a lot!
使ってください！『乾杯』だけど『KP』！
Please do! It's "Kanpai", but "KP"!
KP! KP!
パリピが使ってますよ！
Party people use it!
カリオペ、パリピじゃないけど使います！
Calliope isn't a party person, but I'll use it!
Party people in the house, let's go!
はい！いいですね！
Yes! Nice!
Nice! All right, is the voting closed?
どうかな？どうかな？決まったかな？決まったかな？
How is it? How is it? Is it decided? Is it decided?
決まったかなー？ちょっと分かんない…
Is it decided? I'm not sure...
どうですか、皆さん？『お水おいしい』だって！
How about it, everyone? They're saying "The water is delicious"!
おいしい？おいしい？
Delicious? Delicious?
Okay, oh, closed!
お、1 more call! 1 more call言ってくれてる！
Oh, "1 more call"! They're saying "1 more call"!
I love... Welcome! / Yeah!
Thank you, thank you. あ、今からスタート？
Thank you, thank you. Ah, we're starting now?
今からスタート！
Starting right now!
今からスタート！ Yeah.
Starting right now! Yeah.
Okay, no problem.
Push, push! Go, go, go!
Push please.
ちなみにカリオペのほかのお知らせがあるんだけど…
By the way, Calliope has another announcement...
あの、カバー曲もリリースします！
Um, she's also releasing a cover song!
Yes, check it out! The cover song is "In My Head" by Natori.
Check it out, in my head~
I like song!
I like this song!
You like it?
Yeah!
In my head~
Yeah, please listen to it. 聴いてくださいね。
Yeah, please listen to it. Please listen to it, okay?
Aey!
そう、あの、このライブのあと、そしてそのあとは…メンバー限定です。
Yeah, um, after this live stream, and after that... it's members-only.
はい。
Yes.
はい、そして…
Yes, and...
We have goods! Goods are going to be released very soon, so I wanted to tell you guys about the goods.
We have merch! Merch is going to be released very soon, so I wanted to tell you guys about the merch.
グッズもありますので、Limited...
We also have merch, limited...
Limitedもありますので、ちゃんとお伝え、伝えたかったけど…
There's limited stuff too, so I really wanted to tell you, but...
最後のほう、配信の最後のほうは新CMを流しますので。
Towards the end, at the end of the stream, we'll play a new commercial.
あー！
Ah!
But in about two minutes...
本当にもうすぐ、あの、出るから、あの、そのURL…
It'll really be out soon, that URL...
準備しといて…そうですね、準備しといて…
Get ready... right, get ready...
心も準備して。
Prepare your hearts too.
Oh, check it out! Here it is! Yeah!
えー、かっこいい！
Whoa, so cool!
Dark fantasy! Calliope! / Dark fantasy!
Thank you, I'm so cool! I'm like...
すごい！ / ...a dark fantasy game boss!
Amazing! / ...a dark fantasy game boss!
あの、魔王みたい！
Um, like a Demon Lord!
Yes! / 魔王 is English なに？
Yes! / What is "Demon Lord" in English?
魔王… uh… なんて言えばいいかな…
Demon Lord... uh... how should I say it...
Dark...
Dark King!
Dark King! Yes!
英語うまいよ～。
Your English is so good~
いいですね。
That's nice.
あ、投票終了！
Ah, voting is over!
Voting is over!
It's done! Yay! Thank you so much!
Oh my god, I'm excited to see what you guys chose.
Now then, we should sing one more song then, shouldn't we?
Look out for the goods! Goods URL is dropping soon, there's limited merch.
Look out for the merch! Merch URL is dropping soon, there's limited merch.
Check してね、グッズ買って。
Check it out, buy some merch.
よろしくね！
Please do!
Okay, so, たくさん休みましたね。だから…
Okay, so, we took a long break, right? So...
Let's sing one more song!
もう一曲一緒に歌いたいと思います。
I'd like to sing one more song together with you.
いいですか、皆さん？
Are you ready, everyone?
いいですかー？
Are you ready?
Okay, じゃあ…
Okay, well then...
2人ならやれるさ。
If it's the two of us, we can do it.
やれるさ。
We can do it.
Next song is... Gold Unbalance!
不確かな物語に 勝ち取るはアイデンティティー
In this uncertain story, what we want to win is our identity
あれやこれやと 手を替え品を替え
Trying this and that, changing means and methods,
ドキリと胸を刺す激情
a passion that stabs the chest suddenly.
感情はノンフィクションで喜怒哀楽
Emotions are non-fiction, full of joy, anger, sorrow, and pleasure,
一心同体 一切合切の衝動
one body and one mind, every single impulse.
失敗も成功も味わえ
Taste both failure and success,
我らゴールデンバディ
we are the golden buddy.
意味なんてないような世界で 偶然を重ねた光
In a world that seems to have no meaning, a light formed by overlapping coincidences,
脈打つ鼓動 誰にもなれない
a pulsating heartbeat, weave words that no one else can become.
言葉を紡いでよ
Weave words together!
舐めんなよ 小さな勇気ひとつありゃ十分
Don't underestimate me, just one bit of small courage is enough.
強気に高みへと
Strongly toward the heights,
圧倒絶頂
overwhelming pinnacle.
2人ならやれるさ
If we're together, we can do it.
back-to-back, no matter what 背負ったもん武器に変わるspot
Back-to-back, no matter what, the spot where what we've carried turns into a weapon.
段違い遠くまで飛ばすshout 誰も邪魔できねぇこのroute
A different level, a shout that flies far away, no one can disturb this route.
1等2等3通りって はなからloser
Talking about 1st, 2nd, 3rd options, you're a loser from the start.
うざいくらい貪欲に ハート地獄からかっぱらっちまえ
Greedily to the point of annoyance, steal your heart back from hell.
loop輪廻じゃない routeは無限に
Not a loop of reincarnation, the route is infinite.
ありふれた道じゃない 茨の道を好む玄人
Not a common path, an expert who prefers the path of thorns.
盛大にもう 笑えばいいさ
Just laugh grandly now.
才能煩悩のグラデーション
A gradation of talent and worldly desires,
どうせならぐちゃぐちゃにしてよ
if you're going to do it, mess it all up.
始めたのならやり切る覚悟を
If you've started, have the determination to finish it.
敗者と勝者のduet
Duet of the loser and the winner.
劣等感 弾き出された不条理の屑
Inferiority complex, trash of absurdity that's been ejected,
振り払え貪欲に
greedily shake it off.
志は消えない 2人ならやれるさ
Our ambition won't vanish, if we're together, we can do it.
生きるってなんだ サボった者勝ちか
What is living? Is it better to just slack off?
そんなもの握りつぶせ
Crush that idea.
上辺じゃいられない
We can't stay on the surface,
エンタメライダー
entertainment rider.
人生賭け駆け抜け 絶望も栄光も lemme see you fight back
Bet your life and run through it, despair and glory, lemme see you fight back.
どうなったって何も変わらないんだって
No matter what happens, nothing changes,
ミームされた現実にとらわれて
trapped in a memed reality.
this life where we're stuck taking chances
飽き飽きしてんでしょ？
are you sick of it?
we're living in a world with no direction
reach out with our light 'til we make a connection
tearing the walls apart
facing it all, side by side
once again, it's us against the world
舐めんじゃねーよ
Don't underestimate me
本能をヒリつかせて
Let your instincts burn
本物見せつけろ
Show us your true worth
圧倒絶頂
Overwhelming, pinnacle
アンバランスを踊れ
Dance in the imbalance
踊れ
Dance
アンバランス...
Imbalance...
Thanks for watching, everybody! Thank you to my guests!
Thank you to the band! Thank you, everyone!
Come hang out at Member's Afterparty!
OK! あなたもよろしく！
OK! Best regards to you, too!
Yeah, and buy the goods!
That's about all! You guys, I'm Mori Calliope! Peace out, see ya!
Woo! Let's go! Yeah! Bye!
Yeah, what's up, you crazy skeletons?
I mean... Dearest Dead Beats,
the hour is finally upon us.
The sale of Mori Calliope's birthday celebration goods is about to begin.
On this most auspicious day, you've been granted a great blessing by Death herself.
A most fortunate occurrence for thee,
that such a glorious chest should appear before thine eyes.
Let's take a peek at what the Goddess of Death herself has to offer, shall we?
The journey ahead is long and arduous.
It would do thee good to prepare for it with such luxurious treasures.
Firstly, wouldst thou find comfort in dear Death's embrace?
If it be so, take some warmth along thy journey
with this very large, rollable blanket featuring a most intimidating and battle-ready maiden, yours truly,
designed by my favorite dark fantasy artist, Shimhaq!
The maiden in question possesses artwork in mass from this particular individual,
so I'd be most elated if you bought it for yourself.
Lay it across your bed,
hang it on your wall,
take it with you on an outing,
think of the possibilities!
Secondly, whilst on thy noble journey,
thou mayest come to need a spark of aid.
If it be so, take one of these amulets:
The emblem of a knight to boost your strength,
the emblem of a samurai to grant you additional dexterity,
the emblem of a priestess to bestow additional health to thy weary body,
and lastly, the emblem of a necromancer to grant thee additional intelligence.
Alas, as Fortune be a fickle mistress, thou mayest only receive one in a set.
I pray thee be granted the boon most favorable to thy quest.
Or you could just purchase them all separately if you're looking to speedrun the experience, I suppose.
Thirdly, I present to thee the shining centerpiece of this valuable collection.
Take a moment of repose and sit beside this warm
and healing light, granted unto thee by Death herself:
A lantern to revive thee as many times as needed
throughout even the most daunting of journeys.
May it light thy way to victory,
or to sweet dreams, whichever is preferred.
Enjoy an elegant design chosen specifically by myself.
And of course, how could one continue a journey into vast and unforgiving lands
without a source of healing?
Rejuvenate thyself with this generous flask—or rather, glass—
that seems to refill endlessly upon rest at your lantern.
At least, I think it will.
There really are no guarantees in this life, but give it a try yourself,
see if the myths are true.
Enjoy your favorite beverage during a night of exploring your favorite fantasy scenarios.
But naturally, it would do me no good to leave thee without a... I don't know,
bedtime story?
To put this enchanting collection into context.
So please enjoy a short audiobook-style recording of a fantastical story written by yours truly.
Believe it or not, we are the stars of this tale, so enjoy it on a rainy evening wrapped warmly in Death's embrace.
The... the blanket, I mean.
You can use the flask,
also for like drinking at the same time.
I don't know, just... You should really buy the full set.
And definitely do, because lucky skeletons who act fast and purchase the entire set
will be granted a hand-signed postcard with a special color variant
of Shimhaq's masterpiece rendition of Death herself.
The hand-signed option is in limited supply, so you must be swift.
For those that are unable to secure this extremely rare offering in time, do not fret.
By purchasing the entire set, a duplicated foil-stamped signature postcard
will be sent as a bonus for your purchase.
That is all from me, Death's Maiden and dark fantasy enjoyer, Mori Calliope.
This year's goods are very different from my usual, but I wanted to pay tribute to a genre
that I love so dearly,
and has really made every day of my job so wonderful and happy.
I am so grateful to you guys for coming to enjoy my show as well.
Comment and let me know what your favorite part was,
be sure to like the concert so others may be recommended it,
and subscribe if you enjoy Mori Calliope!
With that, I bid thee farewell,
and happy birthday... to me!
Happy Birthday to me!
6 birthdays, huh?!
今回はいつも以上に特別だったな！
This time was even more special than usual!
ゲストのみんな、Dead Beats、バンドメンバー
To my guests, my Dead Beats, my band,
そして私が飛ぶのを見たいと思ってくれるみんなへ！
and everyone who wants to see me fly,
でっかい愛を！
much love to you all!
もっとハッピーな一年にしようぜ！
Let's have an even happier year!
一緒にな！
Together!
Calliope Mori!
- Calliope Mori